Hello, my name's Tom Brintzenhofe, a certified master mechanic from Reading, Pennsylvania.
Today we're going to talk about how to know when you replace a fan thermostat.
Just for clarity, there is no fan thermostat.
There's either a thermostat that controls the flow of coolant through the engine, or there's a thermostat that will....I mean, a coolant sensor that will turn on an electric fan.
But no fan thermostat.
If you need to replace your thermostat, it's usually in the thermostat...right behind the thermostat housing.
A couple of bolts, two or three hoses, not real hard to change.
Pull it out.
Take your new one, screw it right back in, put your connector back on.
Fill it back up with coolant.
Run it to about a hundred and ninety five degrees.
About two hundred and ten degrees, if it's an electric fan, it will turn on.
Under that, it won't turn on til that point, but just make sure that you keep your hands away from the fan.
You don't want to sit in there and try and turn it, thinking it doesn't work, 'cause it....it turns on on it's own.
And, that can cause a bad day.
The other fans you have, you have a clutch fan that's....that's also a spring.